So we've set up our game so that when we
pick up the power up and then we collide with
our enemy we should get a console statement
saying that we've collided with our enemy.
Now we're going
to add a little bit of
programming so that way
when we actually collide
with the enemy they get sent flying away.
In our player controller
script we're going
to go down to our on
collision enter method.
Now since this is the
place where we actually
interact with our
enemy when they collide
this will be the best place to be
able to do this entire interaction.
Now in our if statement
for our collision we'll
actually need our rigid
body for our enemy
that way we can
actually apply forces to it.
So we'll call it the enemy rigid body.
So we set our rigid
body when we collide with
our enemy we get its
game object and then
we get the component
that we need in this case
we need the rigid body
and then we actually
need to calculate
the direction that we're
trying to go away from
the player so we need
a vector 3 for that direction we'll just
call it away from player and to calculate
this we need to take
the enemy's current
position and subtract it
by our current position.
So now we know what direction the enemy is
coming in and what direction we should send
it back by subtracting
by our current position.
And then last but not least we're
going to apply a force to that rigid body.
So we add a force.
The direction we send
it to is in the direction
of our vector 3 that
we set up away from
the player we'll multiply it by 10 just as
a random value and we want to make this an
instant interaction so we're actually going
to use a force mode and use impulse so that
it applies the force immediately.
Now after I've saved in Unity when I press
play for my game and I pick up this power
up you can see when I hit the enemy it gets
sent flying off in the opposite direction.
Last but not least we're going to
go into our player controller script.
Now we're going to
create another variable just
to hold the actual
strength of that interaction.
So we're going to
make it private since 10
was a pretty good number
maybe we make it 15
just to add a bit more
we'll make it a float and we'll
call it power up strength
and we'll set it to 15.
And then in our on collision
enter where we add the force
and multiply it by 10 we'll
just use power up strength.
Now what you're going
to do is in the player
controller script in on
collision enter inside
of your if statement
you're going to add a
line of code so that we
can get the rigid body
of the enemy and
then you're going to add
another line to get the
direction that we should
send the enemy away
from the player and then
you're going to apply
a force to that enemy
in the direction away
from the player times
our power up strength
variable and make sure
that the force is applied instantly
using force mode dot impulse.
Now it's your turn.